Chris Barnes

Portfolio

www.chrisbarnes.co

Contact Information

(+55) 48 99105 1904 chris@chrisbarnes.co

Nationality

British

SUMMARY

I am a talented designer with experience of UI/UX design, rapid prototyping and front-end development for rich internet applications and mobile devices. I practice user centred design principles, basing design decisions on user needs and business goals.

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer, Chaordic

April 2014 - Present

I research, plan, design and implement engaging user experiences for ecommerce personalisation products; utilising all elements of the User-Centred Design process.

Accomplishments

- Led design projects which reduced product integration times by 10%.
- Designed and implemented a design system across all products.
- Redesigned a number of features based on information gained through usability tests which increased CTR by 40%.
- Designed products which outperformed industry leading competitors in A/B tests with an increase of 26% in sales.

UX Designer, Freelance

February 2011 - April 2014

Worked with a wide range of clients and agencies to design and develop websites and applications focusing on the needs of the end users. My role included performing user-research, identifying requirements, designing and developing websites and/or applications and conducting usability tests.

Accomplishments

- Gained knowledge and experience designing and developing websites for a wide range of users and purposes.
- Designed and developed a number of successful websites which saw an increase in engagement, retention and conversion.

EDUCATION

Edexcel, United Kingdom

HND in Computing and Systems Development — Nov 2012 - Jan 2015

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent (native), Portuguese - Fluent

SKILLS

- User research: Workshops, interviews, surveys and personas.
- Solution design: Ideation sessions, user journeys, card sorting, information architecture, wireframing, UI design, interactive prototypes.
- Usability testing: Guerrilla user testing.
- Software: Sketch, Omnigraffle, Photoshop, Invision, Google Analytics.
- Code: HTML, CSS, SASS, Jquery, Javascript.
- Other: Scrum

REFERENCES

Available upon request.